<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Distributed Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://blog.ritimgitar.com/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Distributed Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <copyright>Baris Goral</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 12:07:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.ritimgitar.com/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prioritization of Value over Power</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritimgitar.com/posts/2021-04-12-power-or-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 12:07:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ritimgitar.com/posts/2021-04-12-power-or-value/</guid>
      <description>Power of Value Product oriented companies that exist and grow by generating value to their customers or potential customers are especially good at prioritizing what to ship and where to invest their energy. They collect sufficient enough data to estimate, validate and pivot their assumptions.
But one can not observe this in government investments or most of the large enterprise companies that I have also been part of since 7 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heaviest Password Generator</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritimgitar.com/posts/2021-02-14-heavypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 12:07:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ritimgitar.com/posts/2021-02-14-heavypass/</guid>
      <description>HeavyPass I think the future of authentication will be passwordless. We are very close to that future but not there yet. Still, most of the applications require username and passwords, but enhancing with additional validation methods (Multi Factor Authentication) like SMS, Authenticator Apps, Biometric scanning etc. In addition to that, users are being forced to change their passwords after some time and mostly not allowed to use one of the last 3 passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://blog.ritimgitar.com/posts/2021-01-07-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:00:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ritimgitar.com/posts/2021-01-07-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>I restarted this blog to go back, remind and remember the fundamentals that brought me here. Fundamentals are the compass that keeps mind and reality together. Joel Goldberg, 45 years experienced software engineering veteran wrote a great article about basics. I put here to remind and remember.
 Focus on the Fundamentals Technology constantly changes, but some fundamental approaches to software development transcend these trends. Here are six fundamentals that will continue to be relevant for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>